♪
[COMMANDER]
Pick up the pace, men!
[BRIGADE] Yes, sir!
[COMMANDER] Hurry,
before someone else
beats us to it!
[BRIGADE] Yes, sir!
We've got a big payday
on the line for this job,
-so be prepared to... Uh?
-[explosion]
[COMMANDER] Huh?
[indistinct shouting]
-[ADVENTURER 1] Up there!
-[ADVENTURER 2] Make 'em bleed!
[scoffs]
We caused some solid chaos.
[IRI] Mm.
[LIDEO] It's unbelievable.
I never thought they'd take
such aggressive measures.
Big Brother,
perhaps we should retreat
through the underground passage.
[LIDEO] No.
The turmoil in the city
will hide us well enough.
Have you called in
all available forces?
It's already being seen to.
Speaking of,
Shiji Bau says
she hired the Iron Whale.
[LIDEO] Is that a fact?
Our backup may not arrive
in time, though.
We'll have to deploy
every adventurer we have
for this battle.
One last matter of business.
It seems we'll have to kill
the man pacted
with the goddess.
Iri, be sure to stay
right by my side.
Yes, I will.
I would gladly give my life
to protect you.
I'm grateful.
A family that's willing to kill
or die for one another...
As it should be,
in a perfect world.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[KIVIA] I bet that bastard Xylo
planned for things
to go the violent route
from the start.
We can only hope
this is all going to plan.
Well, if so,
he's more reckless
than I imagined.
Here we go!
Kill every last one of 'em!
[grunts]
[screams]
You're pathetic.
All right! Who's next in line?
An adequate performance at best.
[MERCHANT] What are they doing?
No way I'm gonna stay open
during a street fight! [gasps]
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] I don't think so.
[grunts]
Take that!
[both gasp]
[MAN 1]
Let's get outta here!
[men panting]
[MERCHANT] Oh, my shop
is completely wrecked.
[man screams]
Xylo, try to show
some restraint!
[XYLO] I'm blocking the way
for reinforcements!
[Kivia gasps]
[boy grunting]
[KIVIA] A child?
What do I do now?
There are so many!
Damn it all!
[FRENCI]
There's no need to fear them.
Simply watch out for their
lower angle of attack.
[KIVIA] But they're kids.
[FRENCI] Too slow.
[boy groans]
Ah, Gwemel's violet lightning.
Did my seal use
demonstrate how to properly
fight them, Holy Knight?
Xylo, care to reveal your plan?
I'm daring to hope there's more
than a smattering of rocks
and berries in that
tiny skull of yours.
Raise as much hell as possible.
Lideo Sodrick
will have no choice
but to pay attention to us.
[FRENCI] My prior comment
was a discredit
to rocks and berries.
I've never heard
such a sloppy plan--
[COMMANDER] Your fun's over!
[scoffs]
Would you be those
pesky troublemakers
wreaking havoc in our city?
[scoffs]
Time to get what you deserve!
[laughter]
Is this supposed to be a joke?
They're entrusting
these ruffians
with protecting the peace?
Sure looks like it.
[scoffs] You have no clue
who you're dealing with, do you?
The top party at the
Ioff City Adventurers Guild!
Stained with blood
and accolades,
we're the famous
Giant-Hunter Brigade!
If you say so.
[commander snarls]
At the ready!
Don't show a lick of mercy!
Lightning staves?
Now fire!
[gasping]
Why don't you lunatics
watch where you're aiming?
Who are these clowns?
They're an embarrassment
and a farce.
[commander laughs]
Fire at will!
Every shot landed
gets a big reward!
No firepower, no accuracy.
They're using fireworks
as battle staves.
You've got this handled!
Come back!
Don't you dare leave us
with these annoying jokesters!
-[Xylo gasps]
-[laughs]
Hope you're ready! [laughs]
[Xylo grunts]
[gasps]
[all grunting]
[screams, grunts]
[ADVENTURER] We surrender.
Any threat against
Xylo or myself
is a declaration of war
on the Mastibolt family.
You will come to regret it.
If you have any regard
for this city,
stop fooling around
and take your jobs seriously!
I was wrong about those two
not getting along. Uh?
[troll growls]
[troll roars]
A troll?
Sodrick actually has
a faerie under his command?
How unfortunate.
I despise dealing
with undisciplined pets.
[footsteps thudding]
[roars]
[troll growls]
[Xylo grunts]
[commander laughs]
Looks like the tables
have turned.
Let's put 'em
out of their misery!
You heard him! Attack!
[all yelling]
[scoffs] You should've
walked away.
[Xylo exclaims]
-[troll growls]
-[XYLO] Dammit.
Ahem.
It would appear that you require
my divine blessing after all.
Errant knight, you have
clearly reaped what was sown
when you
cruelly abandoned me.
Luckily...
my benevolence is such
that I shall now save the day!
The time has come!
March forth to glory!
-Onward! With haste!
-Siena and Zofflec
are going to be
so furious with me.
Wait, who are those weirdos?
This is your last chance.
All of you should run
or surrender now
while you still can.
Otherwise, you're finished.
[footsteps]
[IRI] Brother, this way.
[LIDEO] I won't let them
provoke me into rash action.
We need to keep our heads low
and quietly leave the city.
Ruler of the United Kingdom
of Zef-Zeyal Meht Kioh,
I am King Norgalle Senridge
the First.
-Greetings, loyal subjects!
-[MAN 1] Can it!
[MAN 2] Who the hell are you?
-[MAN 3] Shut up and die!
-[MAN 4] Come and face us!
-[Norgalle grunts]
-[MAN 5] Drop dead!
Seems diplomacy has failed,
and I despise
the remaining option.
Pure vigilante justice.
Yet, there's no choice.
Men, for your crime of treason,
I sentence you to die!
[screaming]
Oh, shit! Stop him!
[NORGALLE] Mmm.
[Tatsuya yelling]
[distant clamoring]
-[horse neighs]
-[KNIGHT] Hyah!
[KNIGHT] Cut 'em down!
Now the cavalry?
Damn you all.
Bastards!
Heads up!
-[horse neighing]
-[KNIGHT 1] What the...
-[KNIGHT 2] Dammit!
-[KNIGHT 3] Let's retreat!
-Time to start the show. [yells]
-[knight screams]
[slashing]
[knight gasps]
[sighs] They never
should've dragged
you little beauties
into this mess.
-Now off you go.
-[horse neighs]
[troll growls]
[Xylo grunts]
-[troll growls]
-[XYLO] Just my luck.
Hurry, Xylo!
We'll distract it for you!
Now, Teoritta!
Ask and you shall receive!
I need you!
-We're taking them down!
-[Teoritta chuckles]
[TEORITTA]
Has your heart awakened
to the necessity
of my blessing, then?
Guess so. I won't argue.
[troll growling]
Captain Kivia, follow me!
Right! Run!
[RAJIT]
Xylo Forbartz, don't fail us.
[XYLO] Let's go.
[TEORITTA] At last!
[troll growling]
Hasten! Let us
end this battle at once!
[troll growling]
[Xylo yelling]
[both grunt]
[Xylo grunts]
[XYLO] You saved us.
Thank you.
Uh, that is hardly sufficient.
It is a knight's sworn duty
to praise his goddess.
[chuckles]
[Xylo grunts softly]
[TEORITTA]
Sweet words of adulation
only have meaning
when they fall from your lips.
Xylo, I so dearly wish
to hear you extol my greatness.
[XYLO] Uh...
-[Teoritta chuckles]
-[Xylo gasps]
[chuckles] You win.
I have to admit,
you are one hell of a goddess.
[TEORITTA] Mm-hmm.
[commander exclaims]
[COMMANDER] I'll be damned.
What's going on?
[NORGALLE]
I trust you've had enough.
Repent for your crimes against
the crown immediately,
and I shall grant
each of you a pardon.
[commander whimpers]
I don't know who you are,
but we surrender!
[indistinct chatter]
How could this happen?
The city my predecessor
entrusted to me.
Big Brother, stay together!
Come on!
Brother!
Iri!
-[sword clangs]
-[DOTTA] Sorry 'bout this.
[Lideo breathes shakily]
[DOTTA] If it helps,
I'd much rather not be involved.
Thing is, a big,
nasty guy threatened me.
I tried my best
to wriggle out of it.
No!
[DOTTA] I feel real bad
about doing this.
But don't worry.
Just come along quietly.
I promise I won't hurt you.
[Lideo breathes shakily]
[BOOJUM] They've caused
quite a commotion.
[SHIJI BAU] This night has
quickly spiraled out of control.
Lideo Sodrick
may already be dead.
[WHALE]
Sounds like things got messy.
I dragged myself out here,
and the client's already dead?
I'm not running a charity.
If there's no pay, I'm out.
[Shiji Bau sighs]
I'll collect my reward,
and leave town while the guild's
in a state of confusion.
And what about you, Boojum?
[BOOJUM] I'm going to go find
and rescue Lideo Sodrick.
Seems like
the polite thing to do.
[SHIJI BAU] Seriously?
[BOOJUM] I do owe the man
a debt of gratitude.
I won't ask you
to help my cause...
-[bee buzzing]
-Mm?
Please excuse me a moment.
[bee buzzing]
Understood.
That's the end of it.
It's all over.
[SHIJI BAU] What is it?
[BOOJUM] New orders.
I'm afraid Lideo Sodrick
will have to rescue himself.
You're both here
to earn money, correct?
How would you like
to embark on a new venture?
-[SHIJI BAU] Explain.
-[Whale chuckles] Who's hiring?
Why, that would be us.
[low growling]
[growls]
-[Shiji Bau gasps]
-[WHALE] Faeries.
[monsters growling]
[BOOJUM] Stop growling.
How very rude of you.
[squeals]
I'm confused.
Does that mean--
[BOOJUM] I'll pay you
for your efforts.
That's the only motivation
humans need
to join our side, isn't it?
[WHALE] I don't have
a problem with it.
As long as I get paid,
I'll work for adventurers,
the Demon Blight.
Anyone, really.
Now, go ahead and tell me
what the job is, boss.
[BOOJUM] I'm not your boss,
so don't call me that.
Our orders are to erase
any evidence
that could possibly link us
to Lideo Sodrick.
Don't leave
a single trace behind.
[WHALE] Not a problem.
That's one of my specialties.
[BOOJUM] I appreciate
your cooperation.
Shiji Bau, have you decided?
I owe you for everything
you've taught me.
For that reason,
I would prefer not to kill you.
[SHIJI BAU] In other words,
you're asking me
to turn against humanity.
[BOOJUM] I assume
that's not going to be
an issue for you?
My time with Lideo Sodrick
taught me an important lesson
about humans.
There's nothing that matters
more to you creatures
than protecting yourselves
and your families.
Well, except, perhaps,
securing benefits
and compensation
that feel proportionate
to your sacrifice.
Prioritizing personal gain above
saving your whole species.
That's just human nature.
Don't bother denying it.
[SHIJI BAU] I won't.
You're absolutely right.
-[commander breathes uneasily]
-[Tatsuya growling]
[NORGALLE]
You're on guard duty.
To atone for your treachery,
I shall put you to work
for my people!
Uh. Right! Get to work, crew!
[BRIGADE] Yes, sir!
[Lideo sighs]
[FRENCI] Xylo,
my men and I will search
the second floor.
If they left
physical evidence behind,
we'll find it.
Repent your lowly deeds!
You must beg forgiveness
for all the suffering
you have caused!
Behold, Xylo, the luster
of my divine grace
rendered this man
speechless!
-[XYLO] Not sure that's it.
-It's as clear as day.
Now speak!
Reveal everything you know!
As leader of this guild,
I was the one who accepted
a generous job request
to kill your whole group,
but I don't know
anything about my employer.
Oh? That is quite unfortunate.
Don't just take his word.
Listen very carefully.
You're in a precarious position
right now.
Normally, I would just
hand you over
to the Holy Knights.
But I'm willing to be
persuaded otherwise.
Hey! We're not here
to negotiate!
You want me to stick
to threats of violence instead?
Pretty sure that kind of thing
doesn't faze him.
[Lideo exhales]
If you'll agree to my terms,
I will negotiate with you.
[XYLO] First,
tell me what you want.
This is about my little brothers
and sisters.
Promise me you'll spare them.
What, you mean those creepy
little kids who kill for you?
[LIDEO] If you can swear
that no harm will come to them,
I would be willing
to trade for that.
-[laughter]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Xylo sighs]
It's a deal.
No, it's not!
You don't have
that kind of authority!
Well, would you rather
we hunt them down and kill them?
Maybe one at a time
in front of him,
real slow and painful.
I wasn't suggesting that at all.
Then you stay out of it.
Anyway, listen.
The trade is simple enough.
Tell us everything you know.
The mission we were given
was to murder the goddess.
Our employer
-said he was a ""coexister."
-[Xylo gasps]
There's that damn
annoying word again.
[LIDEO]
Around ten days ago,
I had my first meeting
with a man in an ornate mask.
He made me an offer.
But in truth,
I didn't have much of a choice.
"Obey, coexist, or die."
After that,
I only had three check-ins
with some intermediaries.
But they have eyes everywhere.
If you want to stay alive,
you have to prove yourself
useful to them.
[XYLO] So you stabbed
humanity in the back
to save your own skin,
when a man like you
could've put up a fight.
The coexisters plan
to yield full authority
to the Demon Lords,
and act as overseers
of the humans beneath them.
A sick hierarchy of slaves,
toiling away for their masters
and Demon Lords.
They've spread
too much corruption.
They've taken countless lives
and so many lands.
Humanity
doesn't stand a chance.
That's why it's crucial
that I toe the line,
and secure a spot
as an overseer.
I made that choice
to save my family.
[XYLO] Keep your damn excuses
to yourself.
I want more useful information,
or otherwise, the deal is off.
There's only
one other thing I know.
The man in the mask
gave me his name.
[XYLO] Tell me,
even if it's likely an alias.
[Lideo breathes shakily]
His name is Mahaeyzel Zelkoff.
[KIVIA] That's preposterous.
Mahaeyzel's the name of a saint.
He was a leader of the Temple
during the First War
of Subjugation, ages ago.
And while we're at it,
the name "Zelkoff" is...
[Kivia gasps]
Wait a minute, are you...
[grunts] My king! My king!
What's this?
We're under fire?
[Lideo exhales sharply]
[WHALE] Not a bad way
to earn some coin.
Don't put up too much
of a fight now.
[TEORITTA] The ceiling!
We've gotta go!
[DOTTA] This is bad!
[JAYCE] They have artillery?
[Dotta grunts]
Xylo, get out of there!
Kivia, get the hell out!
Not yet! He's getting away!
Come back!
Damn. [grunts]
[XYLO] Run for it,
or you're dead!
-[Kivia panting]
-[Xylo gasps]
Incoming! Get down!
What are we up against?
Who attacks like that
inside of a city?
Are they out of their minds?
[XYLO] Dammit. If only we had
Neely with us.
[JAYCE] Hey, don't you dare
blame this on Neely.
I'll murder you.
[XYLO] I didn't blame her.
[NORGALLE]
If the enemy has artillery,
our only option is
to seek out the aid of Rhyno.
Which means
we must break our ally free
from the cell
that's holding him.
[DOTTA] Really?
But that guy's impossible
to work with!
Kivia, we're going
after Sodrick.
Right, of course.
We won't let him slip away.
I have more questions for him.
There's something
I have to know.
Was he telling the truth?
[Lideo pants]
[footsteps]
[IRI] Brother?
[LIDEO] Huh?
Iri?
I'm so glad you're safe.
Brother!
It's over.
I was so worried about you!
[LIDEO] I'm fine.
I survived, just barely.
Though the guild
was destroyed,
at least we're alive.
So where are the other children?
[IRI] The ones
who evaded capture
by the Holy Knights
aren't too far from here.
I'm so grateful.
I had to give in to their
demands to keep us safe,
but it's nothing
for you to worry about.
Elaborate.
Brother, did you
tell them something?
[LIDEO] No.
Nothing important, anyway.
[IRI] Is that so?
-Iri. [grunts]
-[flesh squelching]
[coughs, chokes]
[IRI] Forgive me, big brother.
I had no choice.
[gurgling]
Who are you?
Where's Iri?
Where?
Iri is dead.
I am simply borrowing
her mind and body.
The other children
are over there.
No, it can't be.
My precious siblings.
[cries] You killed my family!
Monster!
[Lideo gags]
This is goodbye,
my former brother.
[Lideo wails]
[Lideo screams]
It appears his incompetence
necessitates
speeding up the plan.
Make preparations
to destroy the city.
Kill all of the humans,
and reduce
everything they've built
to a pile of rubble.
Most importantly,
find the goddess Teoritta,
and then cut her down
by whatever means necessary.
Before that,
may I request a bit of time?
I would like to bury
Lideo Sodrick.
[IRI] You needn't worry
about such things.
Your one and only concern
should be obeying any order
I dole out.
I hope he'll forgive me.
Despite my failure,
I'll always be grateful to him
for buying me books.
Each of you has a role to play,
and I am not just referring
to Boojum.
Of course, you will be
sufficiently rewarded,
just as promised.
Right.
Before we get to the killing,
mind telling us
what we should call you?
[IRI (SPRIGGAN)] Spriggan.
Since you asked nicely,
you may call me "Spriggan."